（火神(かがみ)）うりゃぁぁぁ！
えいっ！
I don't mind entertaining you
（火神）別に構わねえぜ
楽しませてやっても
if you can afford to take it that easy.
そんなゆとりが あんならな
Don't be ridiculous!
（青峰(あおみね)）ざけんな！
You're not ready for that!
（青峰）100年 早(はえ)えんだよ！
I just want to see it again.
（黒子(くろこ)）
見たいんです もう一度
ただ もう一度—
I just want to see Aomine play with a smile again.
青峰君が笑って
プレーする姿を見たい
Ow!
（日向(ひゅうが)）イテッ…
（桜井(さくらい)）あっ…
（日向）でやっ！
Yeah!
よっしゃぁ！
Impressive.
（今吉(いまよし)）大したもんや
（今吉）やはり彼がおると
チームの質が全然ちゃうで
The team is completely different with him.
But doing your best doesn't guarantee victory.
ただなぁ—
真面目に頑張れば
必ず勝てるとか—
It's not that easy.
そんな甘ったるく
世の中できてへんで
（リコ）今吉が黒子君のマーク！？
Imayoshi's on Kuroko?!
shoudou ga atte usoppachi ni idonde
I've got the urge to challenge these bold-faced lies.
boku to kimi to ga shujinkou Love song
You and I are the stars of this love song.
dondon ikimashou
It's time to pick up the pace
Translation Checking: AMS
tsuyoki de semeraretanda
before I lose out to some go-getter,
nakamauchi no warai banashi de wa
and end up like the guys my friends joke about.
Editing: AMS
monmon toshitenda ze
It's starting to drive me crazy...
jibun no heya itsu datte
Always cooped up in my room.
Timing: ninjacloud
honto wa yowaki na peach mind
The truth is, I've got a timid peach mind
K-Timing: Eternal Blizzard
ki no aru soburi ka
Does she have a thing for me?
Typesetting: Darkfire, KmE
Karaoke: KmE
tada no omoikomi ka
Or am I reading too much into it?
baretenda ano ko ni wa
Either way, that girl's got us all figured out.
ganbare otoko no ko
Do your best, boys.
Encoding: Your Mom
kono mama ja sanjuugo renpai
If this keeps up, it'll be 35 straight losses.
kimi dake no boku wa Go to guy
But just for you, I'll be your go-to guy.
he
n
ge
ji
za
i
no
ma
ji
ka
ru
su
ta
a
Phantasmagoric magical star
i
da
na
ru
ma
n
ne
ri
da
t
te
i
ja
na
i
What's wrong with a tried-and-true stereotype?
to
me
ro
a
o
sa
wo
Own up to your own inexperience.
ma
da
mi
chi
nu
ko
i
na
ra
ba
If your love has yet to come full circle,
ze
n
bu
a
ge
ru
ze
I'll give you my all.
ki
mi
ni
chi
ka
u
This I swear to you.
saizen-fansubs.com
Seirin
Touou
Episode
Win Now
（瀬戸(せと)）秀徳(しゅうとく)の高尾(たかお)が持つ
ホークアイでも—
Not even the Hawk Eye of Shutoku's Takao or your spider's web could stop him.
オマエのクモの巣でも
止められなかった
It can't be stopped through spirit.
気合いで どうこう
できるもんじゃないぜ アレは
What is he thinking?
一体 何を 企んでいるのかね
（花宮(はなみや)）フフッ
知るかよ そんなこと
How would I know?
He's the right person for the job though.
けどまあ 適任ではあるが
No one's character is worse than his.
あの人ほど 性格悪(わり)い人間は
いねえからな
（瀬戸）よく分かんないけど
それ オマエが言う？
I don't really know him, but are you one to talk?
（黒子）ハァ ハァ…
ハァ… ハァ…
We've never experienced this before.
（伊月(いづき)）こんなこと初めてだ
Kuroko's passes have been stopped before,
今まで黒子のパスが防がれたことは
何度かあったが—
but we still managed to break through with passes and drives.
それでも パスやドライブで
切り抜けてきた
But this time, it's different.
けど 今回は違う
（木吉(きよし)）ああ…
（伊月）ミスディレクションが
効いてない まさに—
His misdirection isn't working.
They're completely shutting Kuroko down.
完全な“黒子封じ”
Don't be so hard on me.
（今吉）そう 邪険にせんでえな
Let's be friends.
仲良う しようや
Face guard No. 11?
（諏佐(すさ)）
11番にフェイスガード？
If I could do that, I would've done it already.
Touou Academy
Dressing Room
んなもん できたら
とっくにしてるぜ
Even if I'm watching for him, before I know it, he's disappeared somewhere.
（諏佐）注意してても 気がつくと
どっか行っちまうんだよ
That "before you know it" is exactly the point.
（さつき）その“気がつくと”
というのが ミソです
あん？
What?
He's not invisible throughout the entire game.
（さつき）彼は試合中 ずっと
消えているわけではありません
Generally, he's just difficult to notice because of his weak presence.
普段は異常な影の薄さで
認識しづらいだけです
Because he is, you make sure you don't lose sight of him.
しづらいから
見失わないようにする…
However, that gaze is most easily misdirected.
けど そういう視線が
一番 誘導されやすいんです
The harder you try to look at him,
the deeper you fall in his trap.
彼を“見よう 見よう”とするほど
それはドツボ
It makes you an easier target for his misdirection.
ミスディレクションに
かかりやすく なるだけです
How are we supposed to stay on him then?
じゃあ どうやって
マークすりゃあ…
（今吉）おいおい もう
答え 言うとるようなもんやんか
Come on, now.
She practically just told you the answer.
Just don't try to look at him,
見ようと せんかったら ええ
やろ？
right?
He uses his misdirection when coordinating with his teammates.
（さつき）
彼がミスディレクションを
使うのは味方と連携するとき
Just before he does, he always makes eye contact with the player he's coordinating with.
そのために必ず 直前 連携する
選手と アイコンタクトをします
The player he makes eye contact with is a mirror that reflects him.
アイコンコンタクトした選手は
いわば 彼を映す鏡
その選手が見る先に
必ず彼がいます
He will be in that player's vision.
In order to stay on Kuroko without losing track of him,
（今吉）黒子を見失わず
マークし続けるには—
we should look at the mirrors.
つまり 鏡のほうを見ればええ
More than his passes or drives,
（さつき）何よりも脅威なのは
パスやドライブではなく—
the real threat is the misdirection
that supports all his techniques.
そのすべてを支える
ミスディレクションという技術
When that becomes useless, he is powerless.
その無効化は
彼の無力化と同義です
（リコ）ここまで黒子君を熟知した
止め方は おそらく桃井の策
The expert way they're stopping Kuroko now must be Momoi's scheme.
However, a normal player shouldn't be able to detect Kuroko's gaze when he's undetectable.
でも 気配を消した
黒子君の視線なんて—
普通の選手なら
把握することすら 不可能なはず
But he can do it.
（花宮）それが
できちまうんだなあ あの人は
Your senior's amazing.
（山崎(やまざき)）すげえな オマエの先輩
He might actually be smarter than you.
実は オマエより
頭いいんじゃねえの？
頭は知らねえよ ただ—
I don't know how smart he is.
I just wouldn't want to play poker or anything like that with him.
あの人と
ポーカーとか—
そういうたぐいの勝負は
したかねえな
What?
He reads his opponents thoughts by observing their expressions and actions.
（花宮）表情 しぐさなどから
相手の心を読む
腹の探り合いに関しちゃ
妖怪並みだ
He's a monster when it comes to reading minds.
He's practically psychic.
サトリかっつう くらいにな
人が嫌がることさせたら
あの人の右に出るヤツはいねえよ
When it comes to doing things people hate, no one can beat him.
（伊月）あっ… スリー！？
A three?!
Seirin
Touou
Hyuga!
日向！
（日向）お返しだ！ くらえっ！
I'll return the favor. Take this!
（桜井）ええい
（日向）ああっ…
The Barrier Jumper!
（土田(つちだ)）バリアジャンパーが！
Did he predict it?!
（小金井(こがねい)）読まれた！？
The secret to seeing through that quick step back into a jump shot is his center of gravity.
（さつき）
あの長足バックステップからの—
ジャンプシュート
見破るコツは 重心です
Instead of being fooled by his upper body, when he gets the ball, look at the toes of his pivoting foot.
上体にだまされず
ボールを持ったら—
軸足の つま先を見てください
Touou's got this too.
（日向）桐皇(とうおう)には これもあった…
A defense that combines Momoi's projections and data.
桃井(ももい)の予測と データを
取り入れたディフェンス力…
（日向）ええい…
（若松(わかまつ)）ううっ…
Damn it. Their offense is strong enough...
（木吉）くそ…
攻撃力だけなら まだしも…
（青峰）おうおう 勝手に
盛り上がりやがって
Look at you guys having fun by yourselves.
Are you ready for round two, Kagami?
こっちもそろそろ 第２ラウンドと
いこうか 火神！
This guy...
（火神）コイツ…！
（今吉）おっと 行かせへんよ
Whoops.
You're not going anywhere.
As long as I'm on you, you should give up on going to help him.
ワシがついてる以上
助けに行くんは諦めたほうがええで
Kuroko and the upperclassmen have been shut down.
（火神）黒子が封じられ
先輩たちも…
このままじゃ ジリ貧だ
やるしかねえ！
At this rate, we'll just slowly lose.
I have to do it!
You lack focus!
（青峰）集中力 足りねーぜ！
（火神）ううっ しまった！
（伊月･日向）あっ…
Shit!
信じられん…
I don't believe it.
（木吉）ためらったと言うには
あまりにも短い 一瞬の硬直だった
He stiffened for a moment too short to call hesitation.
He can take advantage of that opening?
なのに その隙を突けるのか！？
Wait, damn it!
（日向）待て このっ！
日向！
Hyuga!
くっそお！
Damn it!
He cut around him in a second!
いや だが今の一瞬で
回り込んでる！
いかせるかぁ！
No, you don't!
（火神）なっ… 何！？
What?!
What was that?!
（観客１）うわぁ 何だ 今のは！？
（観客２）もはや人間じゃねえ！
He's not human!
I thought he was giving it his all from the first quarter.
（高尾）前半から本気じゃ
なかったのかよ…
It's simple.
（緑間(みどりま)）単純なことなのだよ
（高尾）え？
What?
Kagami most likely acquired what you'd call "animal instinct."
（緑間）
火神が身につけたものは—
おそらく“野性”と言われる
たぐいのものだ だが—
However...
Kagami isn't the only one with that instinct.
野性を持つのは
火神だけではなかった
それだけの話なのだよ
That's all.
本気でプレーすることが
極端に減ったせいで—
It seems his instincts had dulled since he hadn't been playing seriously as often,
勘が鈍っていたようだが—
but he must be gradually reacquiring them through his battles with Kagami.
火神との戦いで 徐々に
取り戻していったのだろう
Amazing...
（火神）すげえ…
Seirin
Touou
The gap's widening.
（紫原(むらさきばら)）点差 開いてきたね〜
Seirin
Touou
The third quarter's almost over.
（森山(もりやま)）
第３クォーターも 残りわずか
I thought they were doing well too.
いいセン 行ったと思ったが…
What are you talking about? It's not over yet—
（黄瀬(きせ)）
何 言ってんスか 勝負はまだ…
No, they have no chance of a comeback.
（笠松(かさまつ)）
いや もう逆転は… ねぇ
ちょっ 先輩まで…
You too?
Are you saying it's impossible for them to close the gap?
今から この点差を返すのは
無理ってことっスか？
No.
そうじゃねえ 見ろ
Look.
黒子っちのマークが…
Kurokocchi's mark...
Don't tell me...
まさか—
Can they see him?
見えてる…？
The more he uses his misdirection,
the less effective it becomes.
ミスディレクションは 使えば
使うほど 効力が薄くなり—
He can't use it for the entire 40 minutes.
40分フルに
持続することはできない
His misdirection has completely run out.
そのミスディレクションが
完全に切れたんだ
Seirin has no more cards to play.
もはや誠凛(せいりん)に 打つ手はない
There's nothing left.
万策 尽きた
Seirin
誠凛の… 負けだ
lost.
It's nothing to be embarrassed about.
（今吉）
けど 恥じることでもないで
If anything, you did quite well.
むしろ ホンマ 大したもんや
You made it to the Winter Cup with a team of only first and second-years.
１･２年生だけのチームで
ウインターカップ出場
Things would have gone better if you'd had another year to prepare.
あと１年あったら
もっと ええセン 行くやろ
Try again next year.
来年また チャレンジしいや
Hyuga,
（木吉）日向 やっぱり
オマエにだけは言っておくよ
I want to tell you something.
Huh?
（木吉）
オレが一緒にバスケできるのは—
This tournament will be the last time we'll play basketball together.
この大会が最後だ
What?
I thought you'd be good for another year.
そんな １年は
大丈夫なはずじゃあ…
That's what I thought too.
（木吉）オレも
そのつもりだったんだけどな
Maybe it's because I've been playing too recklessly,
今まで 少し無茶したせいか—
but it's been getting worse faster than was expected.
思ったより
早く悪化してるらしい
According to the doctor, there's no way I'll be able to participate in the next Inter-High.
医者が言うには 次の
インターハイはもちろん—
I probably can't play in the Kanto Tournament either.
関東大会も まず無理だそうだ
What's gotten into you, Hyuga?
何だよ 日向
暗くなるとこじゃないだろ？
It's nothing to be sad about.
（木吉）手術より オマエらと
バスケすることを選んだ
I chose to play basketball with you guys instead of having surgery.
I don't regret it a single bit.
オレは これっぽっちも
後悔してないぜ
With Riko, Izuki, Mitobe, Koga,
リコと伊月と
水戸部(みとべ)と コガと—
Tsuchida, Kagami, Kuroko,
土田と火神と黒子と—
降旗(ふりはた)と福田(ふくだ)と 河原(かわはら)と２号(にごう)と
Furihata, Fukuda, Kawahara, and Number 2.
No matter how bright my future would have been after surgery,
例え手術したあと どんなに
明るい未来があったとしても—
I want to fight with you guys now.
オレは今 オマエらと一緒に
戦いたいんだよ
We can't wait that long.
（黒子）そんなに待てません
Next time isn't good enough.
（黒子）
“また今度”じゃ ダメなんです
Not next time...
次じゃない…
We'll win now!
今 勝つんだ！！
None of them have given up.
（桜井）
諦めてない 誰一人！ しかも…
On top of that...
Their fighting spirit hasn't waned.
（若松）闘志はなえるどころか
今まで以上だと…！？
It's stronger than ever!
But there's nothing left for Seirin to do.
（諏佐）だが 誠凛に
もう打つ手はないはずだ！
They're all at death's door.
全員 虫の息 同然…
切り札のミスディレクションも
効果切れや
Your misdirection trump card has run out of steam too.
Spirit alone won't change anything.
気合いだけじゃ 何も変わらんで
（伊月）それは ちょっと違うな
That's not quite right.
It didn't run out. We made it run out.
切れたんじゃない
切れさせたんだ
What?
なっ 消えた！
He disappeared!
（今吉）何やと…！？
What?!
What just happened?
今 一体 何が起きたんだ？
I can't believe Imayoshi couldn't move a muscle.
（原澤(はらさわ)）
今吉君が 一歩も動けないとは…
Is that Izuki's new move?
（さつき）まさか伊月さんの新技？
But that's not possible.
でも あり得ない！
だって 今のは…
After all, that was...
That was Kuroko's...
（今吉）今のは 黒子の…
Vanishing Drive.
バニシングドライブやんけ…！
（リコ）消えたんじゃない
消したのよ！
He didn't disappear, he erased him.
It's a technique that can only be used when Kuroko's misdirection runs out.
（リコ）ミスディレクションが
切れて 初めて使える大技
黒子君の正真正銘
最後の切り札—
Kuroko's true form and final trump card...
Misdirection Overflow!
ミスディレクション･
オーバーフロー！
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
That's impossible!
（今吉）バカな… あり得へん！
Players other than Kuroko can disappear?!
まさか黒子以外の選手が
消えるやと…！？
His movements are distracted!
（日向）散漫だぜ 動きが！
（日向）ええい！
（桜井）ああっ！
Shit!
（今吉）しもたっ！
何ちゅう うかつなパスを…
What a careless pass!
I messed up! Damn it!
不覚や… くそっ！
（桜井）ああ 消えっ…
He disappeared.
You're kidding! Hyuga can do it too?!
（若松）ざけんな おい！
日向もだぁ！？
（日向）ふっ ええいっ！
Seirin
Touou
All right! Another basket!
（小金井）
よっしゃあ 連続ゴール！
We're only ten points behind!
10点差だあ！
（降旗･河原･福田）
うおおお キャプテーン！
Captain!
ハァ…
What's going on?
（今吉）どうなっとるんや これは
Kuroko's misdirection has run out.
黒子のミスディレクションは
確かに切れた
I can see him clearly, so why...
姿は はっきり見えとるのに
何で…？
I can see him?
見えとる… やと！？
ハァ… ハァ…
（リコ）黒子君…
Kuroko...
You want to start in the third quarter?
（日向）第３クォーターの
頭から出る？
It has been tough playing without you,
確かにこの先 黒子が
抜けたままは キツいが…
but will your misdirection last until the end of the game?
けど それで最後まで
ミスディレクションは持つのか？
No, it won't.
いいえ 持ちません
What?
それじゃその後 どーすんだよ
What are you going to do after that?
今までのペースだと—
At this rate, isn't until the end of the third quarter the best we can hope for?
いいとこ 第３クォーターいっぱい
じゃないのか？
When my misdirection runs out,
ミスディレクションが
切れるというのは—
言い換えれば
ボク自身に 視線を—
it will be easier for me to focus their gaze on me.
集めやすくなる
ということでもあります
その状態を逆に利用し—
We can use that to prevent them from looking away from me.
ボクから視線を
外せなくするんです
It will be as though a tenth player suddenly appeared on a nine-player court.
それは極端に言えば—
今まで９人しかいなかった
コート上に—
10人目が突然
現れたようなものです
Immediately afterward, it will be easiest to misdirect their gaze to myself.
その直後 しばらくは
ボク自身が—
一番 視線を
誘導しやすい対象になります
それを みんなのプレーに
合わせるんです
The team should match their plays to that.
Misdirecting his opponents' attention by utilizing the overwhelming presence of Kagami.
（緑間）コート上で
圧倒的な存在感を放つ—
火神を利用することで
相手の視線を誘導する
That's the principle behind the Vanishing Drive.
それが バニシングドライブの
原理だった
Does that mean Kuroko is currently taking Kagami's place?
ってことは—
今のは 黒子自身が
火神の代わりを…？
When Kuroko perfected his Vanishing Drive against Shutoku,
（リコ）秀徳との試合で—
バニシングドライブを
完成させたとき—
he realized the potential of this technique.
同時に彼は この技の
可能性も感じていた
Misdirecting his opponents' vision away, not from himself,
相手の視線を 自分からではなく
味方から外す誘導
but from his teammates.
自分以外の味方全員に—
He grants his teammates the effect of the Vanishing Drive.
バニシングドライブと
同じ効果を与える—
That's Misdirection Overflow!
それが ミスディレクション･
オーバーフロー！
However...
ただし…
However, that technique likely carries several risks.
ただし あの技には おそらく
いくつか リスクがあるのだよ
What risks?
リスク？
Seirin
Touou
The first is time.
Seirin
Touou
（緑間）１つは 時間
Seirin
Touou
Not only can it only be used in the final stages of a game,
Seirin
Touou
試合終盤でしか使えない上に
黒子自身に視線を誘導するのは—
Seirin
Touou
but he should not be able to misdirect attention to himself for long.
Seirin
Touou
そう長くは 持たないはず
黒子１人で
火神４人分の—
He does have to fulfill the role of four Kagamis by himself.
役割を
果たそうっつーんだからな
（緑間）そして もう１つ
誠凛は未来を１つ 捨てている
There's one more risk.
Seirin is abandoning their future.
What?
What Kuroko is doing is like performing a trick while showing how it's done.
（緑間）今の黒子は
ネタばらしをしながら—
手品をやっているような
ものなのだよ
すなわち この試合が終われば…
桐皇相手に—
In other words, once this game ends,
he won't be able to use his misdirection against Touou again.
ミスディレクションは
もう二度と使えない
（緑間）お互い 同じ東京地区
They're both from the Tokyo district.
They're sure to face each other again.
この先も戦うことは
何度もあるだろう
だが 火神や他の選手が
いくら成長したとしても—
However,
even if Kagami and the other players grow,
切り札のない状態で勝てるほど
桐皇は甘くない
they can't defeat Touou without a trump card.
（日向）だあ…
（若松）ぐっ！ はあ…
つまり誠凛は—
In other words, Seirin is entirely abandoning any chance of beating Touou in the future to play this high stakes game?
この大ばくちを
仕掛けるために—
この先
桐皇に勝つための—
可能性を
捨てたってことか？
Are you serious?
マジかよ？
It's still
（黒子）それでも—
better than losing here.
ここで負けるよりマシです
（若松）まだ こんな力が！？
He still has this much strength?
（伊月）ふっ… フン！
（火神）でえい！
We'll worry about the future when we get there.
（黒子）先のことは
またそのとき 考えます
Tetsu...
（青峰）テツ…
Seirin
Touou
With seconds left in the third quarter,
（瀬戸）第３クォーター 終了間際
ひとケタ差まで 追い上げてきたか
they closed the gap to a single digit difference.
（花宮）フンッ
They can't be serious...
（若松）シャレになんねーぜ
こんなん…
This is suicide!
特攻 同然じゃねーか！
Give me a break.
勘弁してくれや ホンマ
ベット 積み過ぎやろ
You're betting too much on this.
Just how far are you going to take this?
どんだけ レート
吊り上げてくんねん
This isn't good.
（今吉）アカンわ
いよいよ この勝負—
If we don't bet everything we have, we won't win this game.
こっちも すべてを賭けな
勝てんようやな
（今吉）フンッ！
He's shooting from there?
（伊月）
そんな位置から 打つのか！？
There's no way it'll go in!
（日向）入りっこねぇ！
（花宮）クフッ
It's not a matter of distance, idiot.
距離とかの問題じゃねえんだよ
バーカ
He's the best at doing things people hate.
人が嫌がることさせたら
一番っつったろ
追い上げムードの
この勢いのまま—
They want to feel like they're catching up
and end the quarter with a single digit difference.
ひとケタ差で
第３クォーターを終えたい
But that's exactly when Imayoshi gets things done.
（花宮）そういうときこそ
決めてくるのが—
今吉って 男なんだよ
（今吉）強いのは認める
I'll admit you're strong.
However,
けどな—
それでも 勝つのはウチや
we'll still win.
ハァ… ハァ…
Kuroko is exhausted.
（リコ）黒子君の消耗が激しい…
With more targets, his Overflow is more mentally taxing than his standard misdirection.
対象が多い分
オーバーフローは—
通常のミスディレクション以上に
神経をすり減らしてるはず
He can't keep this up until the end.
最後までは やっぱり…
Sorry, but could you re-tape my legs?
すまん…
テーピングを
巻き直してくれないか？
（降旗）あ はい！
Sure.
（木吉）最後まで持ってくれ…
Please last until the end.
No, even if my legs break, we have to win!
いや たとえ足が折れても
絶対勝つんだ！
You're thinking too hard, idiot.
（日向）思い詰め過ぎだ ダアホ
That's not a good habit.
悪いクセだぜ
もっとオレらを 信用しろよ
You should have more faith in us.
This team is strong.
このチームは強い
You made this team.
オマエが創ったチームだろ
Win or lose, these are the last ten minutes.
（日向）さあ 泣いても笑っても
これが最後の10分だ
Let's win!
勝つぞ！！
Yeah!
Aomine?
（さつき）青峰君？ 青峰君
Hey, Aomine!
ちょっと 青峰君！
（青峰）あ？ 何だよ？
What do you want?
Don't give me that.
（さつき）
“何だよ”じゃないでしょ！
始まるよ！
The game's starting.
Everyone left.
みんな行ったし
指示とか 聞いてた？
Were you listening to the instructions?
Sorry, I wasn't listening.
（青峰）悪(わり)い 聞いてなかった
What?
Seirin
Touou
Let's start by taking back the points they scored.
まずは さっきやられた分
返してやる
伊月！
Izuki!
It's the Barrier Jumper!
（桜井）
これは バリアジャンパー！
You're not making this shot!
打たせるもんか
（若松）黒子のオーバーフローとの
合わせ技か！
He combined it with Kuroko's Overflow!
（桜井）速いとか
そういう感覚じゃない！
It's not that he's fast!
It felt like time just skipped forward!
まるで 時間が飛んだみたいに…
Seirin
Touou
They brought it back to a single digit difference already.
開始早々
ひとケタに戻してきたか
That buzzer beater didn't do anything to diminish their drive.
あのブザービーター食らっても—
勢いは 全く衰えねぇ！
タフっスねえ 誠凛！
Seirin's tough.
フッ さすがやで
I wouldn't expect any less.
Sorry, I wasn't listening.
（青峰）悪(わり)い 聞いてなかった
ちょっと〜 峰(みね)ちーん
Hey, Minechin.
Sometimes you're so focused you don't listen.
（黒子）青峰君って 集中しすぎて
話 聞いてないとき ありますよね
If you don't listen to the game plan,
you're defeating the purpose.
だからといって
作戦を聞いていなかったら—
本末転倒なのだよ！
いやあ
燃える相手だと ついな！
I can't help myself against a strong opponent.
Hey!
（緑間）おい！
Don't worry.
まあ 心配すんなって
We'll definitely win.
ぜってえ 勝つからさ！
Aomine...
青峰君…
It's slight, but it's definitely true.
（さつき）
少しだけ… けど確かに—
昔の青峰君に 戻ってる…？
He's returned to his former self.
kasunda mirai wo kirisaku you ni terasu hikari
Like a shining light that cuts through the hazy future,
musuu no kanousei wo motome
I chase after unlimited possibilities.
Gotta open my eyes
Wake up sabitsuita me ni hi wo tomose
Wake up, light a fire in your tired eyes.
Get up kusubutteru baai ja nainda zettai
Get up! Now's definitely not the time to let it smoulder.
youi sareta risou nante iranai
You don't need to have some big dream.
yuragu koto no nai ishi to
Just an unwavering spirit,
mikansei na chizu de ii kara
and an unfinished map is enough.
asu wo tsukame kono te de
Hold on to tomorrow with these hands!
detarame na rizumu de nurikaete iku kako ni
Regretting a past that's being overwritten by a nonsensical rhythm...
koukai hitotsu arienai daro
That's not possible, right?
ari no mama no biito de kurikaeshite iku genzei wo
I'll rewrite things with the true beat now,
kasaneta mirai kagayaku you ni
and create a sparkling future.
kizami konda sonzai wo kesshou toshite
Your existence is etched as a crystal.
Keep it in my story
Next Episode
（緑間）青峰を止められなければ
誠凛に勝ち目はないのだよ
If they can't stop Aomine, Seirin doesn't stand a chance of winning.
I know, but...
（黄瀬）
分かってるっスよ でも…
What?!
（黄瀬）なっ…
（緑間）今の動きは？
Those movements!
（黄瀬）火神っちが
一歩も動けなかった？
Kagamicchi couldn't move a muscle.
Did he enter the Zone intentionally?
（緑間）
まさか自分の意志でゾーンに？
Episode
I Believe
Aominecchi's playing seriously!
（黄瀬）
これが青峰っちの本気…